Register of the Dixy Lee Ray papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- GUBERNATORIAL CAMPAIGNS, 1976 and 1980
  - 1980 (Box 115)
    - Speaking engagements
    - Speeches
    - Statements
      - of DLR
      - of other candidates
    - Stickers, flyers
    - Strategy and plans
    - Television appearances and radio broadcasts
    - Town hall meetings
    - "Voter's Calendar"
    - Washington Independent Party
- GOVERNORSHIP, 1977-1981
  - Abbadessa, John (Box 119)
  - Achievements of DLR. Letters of commendation and appreciation
  - Administration
    - "Basic speeches" about the Ray administration
    - Position on energy
  - Affirmative action
  - Appointment books
  - Appointment books (Box 120)
  - Appointments made by DLR
    - General
    - of members of boards and commissions
    - of minorities and women
  - Bills to oppose
  - Boards and Commissions List, 1979 (Box 121)
  - Budget
    - General (4 folders)
    - General (Box 122)
    - Conference notes
      - 1981-1983
      - Agriculture Department (Box 123)
      - Arts Commission
      - Athletic Commission
      - Central Washington State College
      - Commerce and Economic Development Department
      - Community College Education Board
      - Eastern Washington State College
      - Ecology Department
      - Emergency Services
      - Employment Security Department
      - Energy Office
      - Evergreen State College
      - Fisheries Department
      - Gambling Commission
      - Game Department
      - General Administration Department
      - Higher Education Personnel Board
      - Horse Racing Commission
      - Labor and Industries Department
      - Military Department
      - Parks and Recreation Commission
      - Patrol, State
      - Personnel Department
      - Planning and Community Affairs Agency
      - Postsecondary Education Council
      - Public Instruction, Superintendent of (Box 124)
      - Retirement Systems Department
      - Revenue Department
      - Social and Health Services Department
      - Transportation Department
      - University of Washington
      - Utilities and Transportation Commission
      - Veterans Affairs Department
      - Washington State University
      - Western Washington State College
    - Messages of DLR
    - Speaker Duane Berentson floor speech on budget, 31, May 1979
    - Statistics
  - Cabinet and staff (Box 125)
  - Cabinet meeting minutes, 1977
  - Correspondence. See also reading file
    - General (2 folders)
    - Personal file (Box 126)
      - November-December 1976
      - 1977
        - June-September
        - October
        - November
        - December
      - 1978
      - (2 folders), 1978 (Box 127)
      - 1979
        - General (2 folders)
        - January-March
        - April-May (Box 128)
        - June-July
        - August-September
        - October-December
      - 1980
      - 1980-1981 (Box 129)
      - A-B
      - C-D
      - E-F
      - G-H (Box 130)
      - I-L
      - M-N
      - O-P
      - Q-R
      - S-T
      - U-Z
    - Support letters (Box 131)
      - 1977
      - 1978
        - April-August
        - September-December
      - 1979 (Box 132)
        - January-March
        - April-June
        - July-December
      - 1980 (Box 133)
        - January-May
        - June-August
        - September-January 1981
    - Thank-you letters (sent by DLR) (Box 134)
      - 1977
      - 1978
        - January-March
        - April-May
        - June-December
      - 1979 (Box 135)
        - January-June
        - July-December
      - 1980
        - January-June
        - July-January 1981
    - Thank-you letters (sent to DLR) (Box 136)
      - 1977
      - 1978
        - January-June
        - July-December
      - 1979
      - 1980
  - Creston-Mt.Tolman Impact Assistance Project (Box 137)
  - Criminal justice
  - Curriculum vitae submitted to DLR
  - Democratic Governors Conference, Washington, D.C., 25 February 1980
  - Executive orders. See also Mount St. Helens
  - Governor's Economic Forecast Review Committee
  - Higher education (4 folders)
  - Higher education (2 folders) (Box 138)
  - Interviews
  - Invitation log
  - Invitations
    - Received
    - Sent out (2 folders)
  - Legislative meeting schedule
  - Legislative program, 1981
  - McDermott, James - Personal Services Contract
  - Media coverage. See also GUBERNATORIAL CAMPAIGNS, Defeat, 1980
  - Meeting schedule (Box 139)
    - 1978-1979
    - 1980
      - January-May
      - June-September
  - Memoranda
    - General
    - from Louis Guzzo to DLR
  - Messages. See also Budget, Messages
    - to the House of Representatives of the State of Washington, 1979
    - to the Legislature, 1980
  - Minority and Women's Business Development Advisory Council
  - Miscellanea
  - Mount St. Helens - Eruption, 18 May 1980 (Box 140)
    - General
    - Briefing to the legislative leadership, 12 June
    - Chronology of events and specific actions taken by DLR's administration
    - Clippings
    - Contingency plans
    - Correspondence
    - Disaster Assistance Center
    - Disaster Preparedness Plan - Department of Emergency Services
    - Editorial opinions (Box 141)
    - Executive orders
    - Federal Emergency Management Agency
    - Final Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Bill for Fiscal, 1980
    - Health implications
    - Memoranda
    - Miscellanea
    - Notes
    - Press conferences
    - Press releases
    - Printed material
    - Radio Amateurs Civil Emergency Services
    - Recovery Assistance Team
    - Request for federal aid
    - Statements, declarations
    - Studies, reports (Box 142)
    - Testimonies
    - Watch Group
  - National Governors' Association. See also SUBJECT FILE, Energy, Nuclear, Wastes, Low-level (Box 143)
    - General
    - Committees
      - Natural resources and environmental management
      - Transportation, Commerce and Technology
    - Conferences
      - 1977
      - 1980
  - Notes (Box 144)
  - Office
    - Decoration of
    - Organization
    - Procedures, guidelines
  - Pension systems
  - Personal Services Contract of DLR - Termination
  - Petitions presented to the governor
  - Powers and duties of the governor
  - Press conferences
  - Press office
  - Press releases
  - Prisons
    - General (2 folders)
    - McNeil Island
      - General
      - General (2 folders) (Box 145)
      - State plan for utilization
  - Proclamations
  - Reading file
    - Daily memoranda from DLR's secretary
    - Sorted correspondence, (7 folders), January 1977 (Box 146)
  - Reports of DLR on her years in office (Box 147)
    - lst, 1978
    - 2nd, 1979
    - 3rd, 1980
    - 4th, 1981
  - Salaries
  - Senior citizens
  - Speech notes
  - Speeches (arranged alphabetically by name of requesting group or occasion). See also State of the state addresses
    - Unidentified
    - Aberdeen Rotary Club, Aberdeen, Washington, 29 November 1978 (Box 148)
    - Adult Day Services, Olympia, Washington, 14 November 1979
    - Aikens Lecture Series (University of Vermont), Burlington, Vermont, 13 April 1980
    - ALCOA Political Action Committee, Vancouver, Washington, 8 February 1980
    - All-City Service Clubs, Spokane, Washington, 20 December 1979
    - Allied Daily Newspapers, Spokane, Washington, 19 May 1978
    - Aluminum Association, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, 25 May 1978
    - American Academy of Achievements, Salt Lake City, Utah, 23 June 1979
    - American and Canadian Hospital Associations, Montreal, Canada, 31, July 1980
    - American Association of Community and Junior Colleges, San Francisco, California, 2 April 1980
    - American Business Women's Association, Spokane, Washington, 31, May 1980
    - American Gas Association, Seattle, Washington, 15 May 1980
    - American Industrial Development Council, Seattle, Washington, 21, May 1979
    - American Judges Association, Seattle, Washington, 23 October 1978
    - American Legion, Annual State Convention
      - Seattle, Washington, 21, July 1978
      - Spokane, Washington, 20 July 1979
    - American Public Power Association Conference, Seattle, Washington, 18 June 1979
    - American Red Cross, location unknown, 13 March 1980
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers
      - San Francisco, California, 13 December 1978
      - Tri-Cities, Washington, 19 March 1980
    - Anchorage Chamber of Commerce, Anchorage, Alaska, 23 July 1979 (Box 149)
    - ANS/ENS International Meeting on Fast Reactor Safety Technology, Seattle, Washington, 22 August 1979
    - Apprenticeship Training Building dedication, Spokane, Washington, 25 April 1980
    - Arbor Day, Olympia, Washington
      - 12, April 1978
      - 11 April 1979
    - ARCO Petroleum Products Co. - Cherry Point Refinery, Ferndale, California, 16 July 1980
    - Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges - National Conference on Trusteeship, Miami, Florida, (delivered by Louis Guzzo), 9 April 1979
    - Association of Graduate Schools of the American Association of Universities, Seattle, Washington, 9 October 1979
    - Association of State Budget Officers, Seattle, Washington, 7 June 1978
    - Association of the U.S. Army, the Air Force Association and the Navy League of the United States, location unknown, 5 March 1977
    - Association of Traffic Safety Representatives, Olympia, Washington, 25 March 1980
    - Association of Washington Business
      - Spokane, Washington, 10 May 1978
      - Seattle, Washington, 23 October 1979
    - Association of Washington Business and the Washington Association of Community Colleges, Seattle, Washington, 12 March 1980
    - Association of Washington Cities
      - Yakima, Washington, 14 June 1978
      - Olympia, Washington, 18 June 1980
    - AT&T Shareholders, Seattle, Washington, 18 April 1979
    - Bellevue and Redmond Chambers of Commerce, Bellevue, Washington, 5 March 1979
    - Bond Attorneys' Workshop, Rosement, Illinois, 12 October 1979
    - Bonney Lake Library, Bonney Lake, Washington, 13 July 1979
    - Boy Scouts of America, Evergreen, Washington, 7 March 1980
    - Bryn Mawr College, Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania, 10 May 1980
    - Burlington Northern Credit Union, Tacoma, Washington, 15 February 1980
    - Business Council, Hot Springs, Virginia, 9 May 1980
    - Business Week - Government Day, Olympia, Washington, 5 March 1979
    - Camas/Washougal Chamber of Commerce, Washougal, Washington
      - 14 (delivered by Dean Cole), September 1978
      - 27 August 1980
    - Capitol-125th anniversary, Olympia, Washington, 28 November 1978
    - Capitol City Press Club and Washington State Information Council, Olympia, Washington, 14 May 1978
    - Chehalis Rotary Club, Chehalis, Washington, 7 March 1979
    - Chehalis Rotary Club and Centralia Kiwanis Club, Chehalis, Washington, 9 August 1979
    - Clallam County Courthouse dedication, Port Angeles, Washington, 1 March 1980
    - Clatskanie Kiwanis Club, Clatskanie, Washington, 23 June 1978
    - Concrete Technology Corporation, location unknown, 26 April 1979 (Box 150)
    - Cooperative Energy Conservation Demonstration, Spokane, Washington, 27 August 1980
    - COPE, Seattle, Washington, 7 October 1978
    - Dairy Farmers of Washington, Olympia, Washington, 2 July 1980
    - Department of Accounts, Washington State - Training Conference, Olympia, 8 June 1979
    - Department of Commerce and Economic Development, Washington State - "Picture Perfect Washington" Contest Kick-Off. See Speeches, Pay n' Save Corp.
    - Department of Ecology, Washington State - Signing of Snoqualmie Basin Mediated Agreement, Carnation, 27 October 1978
    - Department of Fisheries, Washington State
      - Bear Springs Salmon Hatchery dedication, Near Forks, 28 August 1980
      - Donald L. McKernan Salmon Hatchery dedication, Near Shelton, 17 August 1979
      - Edmonds Fishing Pier opening, Edmonds, 15 March 1979
      - Humptulips Salmon Hatchery dedication, Humptulips, 22 July 1978
      - Hurd Creek Salmon Hatchery dedication, Near Sequim, 28 August 1980
      - Trevor Kincaid Shellfish Laboratory dedication, Point Whitney, 17 August 1979
    - Department of Licensing, Washington State
      - Driver License Renewal Office opening, Seattle, 13 June 1978
      - East Washington Real Estate Office opening, Spokane, 9 July 1980
    - Department of Social and Health Services, Washington State - Management Development Program, Olympia, 8 June 1980
    - Department of Veterans Affairs, Washington State - Nursing Care Facility and Sculpture "The Legacy" dedication, Orting, 5 September 1979
    - Disabled American Veterans "State Convention," Wenatchee, Washington, 14 June 1979
    - Economic Development Executives of Washington, Seattle, Washington, 26 October 1978
    - Education Commission of the States, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 6 and 16 April 1978
    - Ellensburg Chamber of Commerce, Ellensburg, Washington, 9 October 1978
    - Elma Chamber of Commerce, Elma, Washington, 5 April 1979
    - Filipino Community Center, Seattle, Washington, 21, June 1980
    - Fort Simcoe Council - Boy Scouts of America, Yakima, Washington, 26 March 1980
    - Foundation for International Understanding through Students, Olympia, Washington, 2 August 1979
    - Frank Lucas Homestead dedication - Chelan, Washington, 26 May 1979
    - Friends of Governor Dixy Lee Ray, Seattle, Washington, 15 May 1978
    - Friendship Force Program, Olympia, Washington, 4 June 1978
    - Goldendale Junior Chamber of Commerce, Goldendale, Washington, 5 October 1979
    - Governor's Birthday Speech, Olympia, Washington, 3 September 1980
    - Governor's Conference on Aging
      - Centralia, Washington, 8 April 1978
      - Spokane, Washington, 22 April 1978
      - Yakima, Washington, 6 May 1978
      - Lynnwood, Washington, 20 May 1978
    - Governor's Conference on Child Abuse and Neglect, Olympia, Washington, 30 April-3 May 1978
    - Governor's Conference on Child Safety, Olympia, Washington, 4 June 1979
    - Governor's Conference on Hiring the Job Ready Ex- Offender, Seattle, Washington, 6 July 1979
    - Governor's Conference on Housing, Tumwater, Washington (Box 151)
      - 22 February 1979
      - 10, April 1980
    - Governor's Conference on Library and Information Services, Olympia, Washington, 23 April 1979
    - Governor's Conference on Travel, Seattle, Washington, 9 November 1978
    - Governor's Writers' Day, Olympia, Washington
      - Open House, 20 September 1978
      - Presentation of awards, 17 May 1979
    - Grays Harbor Democratic Central Committee, Aberdeen, Washington, 28 October 1978
    - Heritage Foundation - "Growth Day," Washington, D.C., 17 April 1980
    - Homebuilders Association, Richland, Washington, 12 November 1979
    - IBPOE of Washington (Elks), Tacoma, Washington, 15 July 1978
    - Idaho and Washington Association of Carpenters, Moscow, Idaho, 10 April 1980
    - Industrial Research Development Council, Portland, Oregon, 19 May 1980
    - Industrial Safety and Health Conference, location unknown, 15 November 1979
    - International Association of Clerks, Recorders, Election Officials and Treasurers, Seattle, Washington, 13 July 1980
    - International Association of Geomagnetism and Aeronomy and the International Association of Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics, Seattle, Washington, 22 August 1977
    - International Peace Arch Association, Blaine, Washington, 11 June 1978
    - International Symposium on Radiopharmaceuticals, Seattle, Washington, 19 March 1979
    - Japan-America Society of Seattle, Seattle, Washington, 23 February 1979
    - Jefferson-Jackson Day dinner
      - Port Angeles, Washington, 22 September 1978
      - Olympia, Washington, 20 October 1978
    - Joint Chambers of Commerce meeting, Tukwila, Washington, 7 July 1980
    - Joint Council of Teamsters No.28, Seattle, Washington, 27 August 1979
    - Keep Washington Green, Olympia, Washington, 2 May 1980
    - Kennewick/Pasco Bridge dedication, Washington, 16 September 1978
    - Kitsap Brokers' Multiple Listing Service, Bremerton, Washington, 23 July 1980
    - Lake City Chamber of Commerce, Seattle, Washington
      - 24 October 1979
      - 19 April 1980
    - Lakeland Village dedication, Medical Lake, Washington, 9 June 1979
    - League of Women Voters, Spokane, Washington, 22 May 1978
    - League of Women Voters of Washington, Seattle, Washington, 23 May 1979
    - Lewis and Clark Trail Heritage Foundation, Inc., Vancouver, Washington, 14 August 1978
    - Lockheed Management Club, Seattle, Washington, 12 February 1980
    - Martin-Marietta Aluminum, Goldendale, Washington, 5 October 1979
    - Medal of Honor Recipients, Olympia, Washington, 9 November 1979
    - Mexican Americans, Tacoma, Washington, 5 August 1979
    - Mexican Community House, Tacoma, Washington, 21, June 1980
    - MOD-2 Wind Turbine Generators construction start ceremony (Bonneville Power Administration), Goldendale, Washington, 11 April 1980
    - Mother Joseph Foundation (Box 152)
      - Campaign kick-off, Vancouver, Washington, 3 October 1978
      - Benefit Dance, Vancouver, Washington, 1 March 1980
      - Dedication, Washington, D.C., 1 May 1980
      - Remarks, Olympia, Washington, 9 October 1980
    - National Association of Tax Administrators - Conference on Revenue Estimating, Seattle, Washington, 22 October 1979
    - National Automobile Dealers Association, Vancouver, British Columbia, 20 June 1978
    - National Conference of Regulatory Attorneys, Olympia, Washington, 20 May 1980
    - National Convention of Democratic Women's Clubs, Seattle, Washington, 21, April 1979
    - National Council of Jewish Women, Seattle, Washington, 16 March 1980
    - National Freight Traffic Association, Palm Beach, Florida, November 1977
    - National Governors Association - White House International Trade Conference, Seattle, Washington, 6 June 1979
    - National Guard Association of Washington
      - Ocean Shores, Washington, 20 May 1978
      - Wenatchee, Washington, 28 April 1979
    - National Milk Producers Federation, Seattle, Washington, 27 November 1978
    - New Hope Training Center for the Handicapped, Spokane, Washington, 31, May 1979
    - Northern State Multi-Service Center dedication, Near Sedro Woolley, Washington, 14 July 1979
    - Northwest Center for the Retarded, Seattle, Washington, 28 July 1980
    - Northwest Electric Light and Power Association, Spokane, Washington, 25 September 1978
    - Northwest Regional Conference on the Emerging International Economic Order, Seattle, Washington, 30 March 1979
    - Northwest Regional Energy Conference, Seattle, Washington, 1 June 1978
    - Northwestern University Traffic Institute's Northwest/Southwest Combined Grad Retraining seminar, Tukwila, Washington, 16 July 1980
    - Nuclear Energy Women, Bellevue, Washington, 14 September 1979
    - Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, D.C., 6-7 November 1979
    - Nuclear Waste Disposal Conference, Stanford, California, 20 November 1979
    - Okanogan Town Hall meeting, Okanogan, Washington, 20 August 1980
    - Olympia Downtown Kiwanis Club, Olympia, Washington, 2 April 1979
    - Oregon/Washington Hotel Motel Operators, Rosario, Washington, 2 June 1980
    - Oregon, Washington, Idaho Chambers of Commerce Officers and Managers Conference, Portland, Oregon, 11 February 1980
    - Pacific Coast Association of Port Authorities, Vancouver, Washington, 8 August 1979 (Box 153)
    - Pacific Coast Society of Orthodontists, Vancouver, British Columbia, 2 October 1978
    - Pacific Logging Congress, Spokane, Washington, 16 November 1978
    - Pacific Northwest Bell, Seattle, Washington, 18 April 1979
    - Pacific Northwest Metals and Minerals Conference, Seattle, Washington, 8 May 1980
    - Padilla Bay Estuarine Sanctuary, Anacortes, Washington, 18 May 1979
    - Pay n' Save Corporation
      - "Picture Perfect Washington," Seattle, Washington, 11 May 1979
      - Ribbon cutting ceremony, Seattle, Washington, 6 September 1979
    - Phi Chi Theta and Alpha Kappa Psi Fraternities, Renton, Washington, 21 October 1978
    - Philippine Independence 82nd Anniversary, Seattle, Washington, 14 June 1980
    - Pierce County Democratic Luncheon Club, Tacoma, Washington, 21, April 1980
    - Pine Lodge Correctional Center dedication, Near Medical Lake, 13 April 1978
    - PNRC meeting, Vancouver, Washington, 15 December 1978
    - Port of Kalama Marina Complex, Kalama, Washington, 16 July 1977
    - Poulsbo Noon Lions Club, Poulsbo, Washington, 28 June 1979
    - Propeller Club, Seattle, Washington, 22 May 1979
    - Providence Medical Center dedication, Seattle, Washington, 24 July 1980
    - Raleigh Hills Hospital, Spokane, Washington, 18 May 1978
    - Realtors, Bellingham, Washington, 1 February 1980
    - Redmond Rotary Club, Redmond, Washington, 14 January 1980
    - Regulatory Attorneys, Olympia, Washington, 20 May 1980
    - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, New York, 26 May 1978
    - Retsil Veterans Home Nursing Facility dedication, Retsil, Washington, 3 June 1980
    - Reynolds Aluminum
      - Recycling Plant opening, Kent, Washington, 7 December 1979
      - Luncheon, Olympia, Washington, 8 July 1980
    - Richland Chamber of Commerce, Richland, Washington
      - 26 April 1978
      - 28 April 1980
    - Rockwell Hanford Management Club, Richland, Virginia, 14 May 1980
    - Rocky Mountain Mineral Law Institute, Seattle, Washington, 12 July 1979
    - Scottish Rite Freemasonry Temple, Seattle, Washington
      - 18, March 1980
      - 9 April 1980
    - Seattle and Charlotte, N.C. Chambers of Commerce, Seattle, Washington, 19 September 1978 (Box 154)
    - Seattle Building and Construction Trades Council, Seattle, Washington, 23 June 1978
    - Seattle Chamber of Commerce, Seattle, Washington
      - 9 February 1979
      - 4 December 1979
      - l, July 1980
    - Seattle Community Development Round Table, Seattle, Washington, 26 March 1979
    - Seattle Downtown Kiwanis Club, Seattle, Washington, 17 July 1979
    - Seattle Food Brokers, Bellevue, Washington, 12 September 1980
    - Seattle Hearing and Speech Center, Seattle, Washington, 3 April 1978
    - Seattle-King County Board of Realtors, Seattle, Washington, 16 March 1979
    - Seattle Rotary Club, Seattle, Washington, 16 January 1980
    - Seattle Savings League, Seattle, Washington, 15 July 1980
    - Senior Citizens - Bill signing ceremony (HB 491), Olympia, Washington, 9 May 1979
    - Senior Citizens Convention of Pacific County, Naselle, Washington, 31 January 1979
    - Shoreline Rotary Club, Seattle, Washington, 19 August 1980
    - Simpson Timber Heroic Awards, Olympia, Washington, 11 August 1980
    - Snohomish County Cities and Towns Association, Edwards, Washington, 24 July 1980
    - Sons of Italy, Olympia, Washington, 25 May 1979
    - Soroptimist Club, Kiwanis Club and Lions Club, Yakima, Washington, 11 March 1980
    - Southwest Washington Contractors Association, Vancouver, Washington, 20 June 1979
    - Spokane Board of Realtors, Spokane, Washington, 31, May 1979
    - Spokane Club, Spokane, Washington, 13 April 1978
    - Spokane Community College, Spokane, Washington, 8 June 1978
    - Spokane Mayor Ron Bair, Spokane, Washington, 6 October 1979
    - St. Regis Paper Co. Foreman's Club, Tacoma, Washington, 21, January 1980
    - Standard Oil Co. (Chevron USA), Seattle, Washington, 9 September 1979
    - State Parks and Recreation Commission, Fort Worden State Park, Washington, 4 March 1980
    - Superior Court Judges Association, Port Ludlow, Washington, 27 March 1980
    - Tacoma-Pierce County Bar Association, Lakewood, Washington, 16 February 1979 (Box 155)
    - Tacoma Urban League, Tacoma, Washington, March 1979
    - Tacoma Women's Club, Tacoma, Washington, 18 May 1978
    - Toppenish Education Association, Yakima, Washington, 6 May 1980
    - Trooper Cadet Class, Olympia, Washington, 17 December 1979